João Dias Front-end developer



I make stuff for the web.

I'm João — a developer based in Coimbra, Portugal.

I've been working in this industry for over 10 years and now mostly specialized in front-end development, web accessibility and testing for all kinds of screen sizes and users.

Feedzai is where I work since 2019 fighting the good fight against financial fraud but I also enjoy my side projects.

Experience

Senior Front-end Engineer

2019 - Today

Web Developer 2013 - 2019

UI Designer 2011 - 2013

Web Designer 2011 - 2013

FEEDZAI

Front-end development, design systems, testing, mentoring and coaching.

WIT SOFTWARE

Main focus on interface design as well as front-end web development.

LOAD INTERACTIVE

The do-it-all-designer at a mobile development startup.

JOAODIAS.ME

Early years as a freelance web designer.

Education

ESEC, Portugal Class of 2011

ESEC, Portugal 2007 - 2008

Bernardino Machado School Class of 2007 Degree in Communication and Multimedia Design

1st year in Organizational Communication

High School in Computers and Informatics

Skill set

VISUAL TOOLS

Sketch, Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator and Indesign.

DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Jest, Cypress, Web Accessibility, Gatsby, Next, jQuery, Wordpress, Git.

OTHERS

User Research, Usability, Video and Audio production.

Others

Besides taking the time to learn new skills every week, I also enjoy spending family time -- specially with my son -- as well as the usual workout and rocking out to some good rock, metal and other types of good music.